RESUME

Manohar Singh DOB:13thMay 1991 Address: Lucknow (u.p)



manohar.singh935@gmail.com



+91-8882610010



Profile

An experienced marketing professional with around 6+ years of experience in the areas of across Product Marketing, Marketing Management, Brand Management, Key Account Management, Public Relations and Sales Promotion activities.

Key Skills

- 1. Business Development
- 2. Brand Management
- 3. Process Management
- 4. Communication Strategy
- 5. Marketing

- 6. Operation Management
- 7. Customer Targeting
- 8. Experience in E-commerce
- 9. Public Relation
- 10. Competition Analysis

Experience

Classic Marble Pvt Ltd, Lucknow

Sales and Marketing From Jan 2022 – Till Date



Key Learning's:

- New Business Sales and Expansion plan
- > Strategies and plan for increasing business in new geographies.
- Connect with new Architects/Contractors in untapped potential of expansion of local market.
- Reactivation of old/lost customers/dealers.
- > Promote and encourage efforts/strategies for all business line to focus on cross sell and deep sell for all products of the company.
- > Implementing sales strategies and plans to meet revenue goals.
- Managing team of BDE's reporting to achieve targets, assisting in order closing.
- Support BDE's to connect with new clients and meetings.
- > Daily meetings plans and follow up on leads and meetings, following up with the leads generated till finalization of orders
- Follow up on payments as per collection plan.
- > Increase the Brand Value representing the company by creation of Strategy / Plan around it and ensuring implementation.
- To represent in various forum for networking and brand building of HNI business forums of builders, Interior designer, architects and other forums.
- Conduct dealers connect and meetings at regular intervals.

MPG Stone Pvt Ltd, Gurgaon

Sales and Marketing, since April 2019 – Dec 2021



Key Learning's:

- ➤ Handling Sales and Marketing activities for stone products.
- Visit the construction sites and gathers the data as required by mapping.
- > Identify new prospects Meeting with Architects, dealers and distributors.
- Business Development via Calling, Mailing, Cold Calling, Inside Sales, Market research, B2B Sales.
- Meet assigned sales quotas, manage the pipeline and acquire new business.
- Pro-actively identifying new business opportunities and to focus on the acquisition of new business opportunities.
- For business development, exploring India market for existing and new products.
- Follow-up with the vendors for regular procurement of goods for the existing orders.

Benny Impex Pvt Ltd, Delhi Ncr

Sales & Marketing, From August 2016 – Feb 2019





Key Learning's:

- > Appointing new distributors in the territory.
- > Demonstrate the product to higher authorities of corporates and dairy industries.
- Conducting sales activities in the corporates (Hospitals, Sweetshops, Gym, Hotels) in order to increase the number of customers and sales volume.
- Maintaining CRM to increase business sales and improving sales forecasting for business development.
- > To be aware of the competing products and demand –supply variation

Education

- ➤ MBA in Marketing(Major) with International Business(Minor) from Army Institute of Management & Technology, Greater Noida (2014-2016)
- ➤ Completed Graduation BBA, IMS Noida(2011-2024)
- > 12th From KV Delhi Cantt (2010 2011)
- ➤ 10th From KV Delhi Cantt (2008-2009)

Extra/Co-Curricular Activities

- Winner of corporate walk AIMT annual fest.
- ➤ Have worked as a member of The Marketing Club, the Events Committee and Mess committee. Have also worked in teams and been an active player in organizing many events.
- ➤ Won Second Position in Chef Competition.

Hobbies/Interests





